Bernarda Bryson Shahn
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Exhibition Files, 1955-2000, Series 5:; (Box 9; 5 folders)
  These files contain letters, notes, and printed material concerning exhibitions of art work by Ben Shahn.
  - Ben Shahn Exhibition in Spoleto, Italy, 1955-1958, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 19-20)
  - Ben Shahn Exhibition at the Salas Pablo Ruiz Picasso in Madrid, Spain, 1983-1985 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Ben Shahn Exhibition at the Starr Gallery in Newton Centre, Massachusetts, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Ben Shahn Exhibition at the Tama Art University Museum in Kaminoge, Tokyo, Japan, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Personal Business Records, 1932-2001, Series 6:; (Box 9, 10; 0.8 linear feet)
  Personal business records include of files concerning property owned by Bernarda Bryson Shahn 's parents, the Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, art legislation matters, miscellaneous contracts, files documenting Bernarda Bryson Shahn 's interactions with Harry N. Abrams, Inc. and the Midtown Galleries, records of payments and royalties from miscellaneous publishing houses, price lists, income tax records, loan agreements, insurance records, and miscellaneous receipts.
  - File Concerning Property Owned by Bernarda Bryson Shahn 's Parents, 1965-1968 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - File on Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, 1968-2001, (5 folders) (Box 9, Folder 25-29)
  - File Concerning Art Legislation, 1976-1992, undated, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 30-31)
  - By-Laws of Roosevelt Arts Project, Inc., 1996 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Contracts, 1954-1990, undated, (4 folders) (Box 9, Folder 33-36)
  - File Concerning Harry N. Abrams, Inc., 1971-1994, undated, (4 folders) (Box 9, Folder 37-40)
  - File Concerning Midtown Galleries, 1983-1994, undated, (5 folders) (Box 9, Folder 41-45)
  - Records of Payments from Publications, 1946-1967 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Royalty Statements: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1969-1973 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Royalty Statements: Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc., 1960-1984, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 48-50)
  - Royalty Statements: Houghton Mifflin Company, 1956-1973 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Royalty Statements: Little, Brown and Company, 1960-1969 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Royalty Statements: Macmillan Company, 1966-1973 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Royalty Statements: Visual artists' and Galleries Association, Inc. (VAGA), 1992-1996 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Miscellaneous Royalty Statements, 1949-1970, undated (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Price Lists for Art Work, 1960-1999, undated, (6 folders) (Box 9, Folder 56-61)
  - Records of Works Sold, 1956-1988 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Payment Receipts for Art Work, 1934-1996 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Income Tax Records, 1948-1990 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Loan Agreements, 1955-1999, undated, (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 4-6)
  - Deeds of Gift, 1970-1999, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Insurance Records, 1969-1996 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Requests for Permission to Reproduce Images, 1963-1999 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Shipment Receipts, 1963-1997, undated, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
  - Miscellaneous Receipts, 1941-1997, undated, (3 folders) (Box 10, Folder 12-14)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1932-1994, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Printed Material, 1904-2004, Series 7:; (Box 10-11, 13, OV 14-15; 1.2 linear feet)
  Printed material includes clippings, prospectuses, exhibition announcements and catalogs for Bernarda Bryson Shahn, Ben Shahn, and others, press releases, calendars of events, programs, miscellaneous brochures and booklets, books including A Partridge in a Pear Tree, illustrated by Ben Shahn, reproductions of art work, and miscellaneous printed material.
  - Clippings, 1904-2004, undated, (31 folders) (Box 10, Folder 16-46)
  - Clippings of Bernarda Bryson Shahn 's Illustrations, undated, (6 folders) (Box 10, Folder 47-52)
  - Prospectuses, 1939-1993, undated (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1933-2002, undated, (11 folders) (Box 10, Folder 54-64)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Ben Shahn, 1932-2002, undated, (10 folders) (Box 10, Folder 65-74)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Abby Shahn, 1987-1988 (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Jonathan Shahn, 1972-2001, undated, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 76-77)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Judith Shahn, 1979-1996, undated (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs for Others, 1961-2002, undated, (2 folders) (Box 10, Folder 79-80)
  - Press Releases, 1964-1998, undated, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - Calendars of Events, 1970-2000 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Programs, 1967-1996, undated, (3 folders) (Box 11, Folder 4-6)
  - Brochures for the Sale of Art Work, 1969-1994, undated, (3 folders) (Box 11, Folder 7-9)
  - Brochures for Art Classes, 1991-1997, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Brochures for the Sale of Books, 1967, undated, (2 folders) (Box 11, Folder 11-12)
  - Miscellaneous Brochures, 1982-1999, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Booklet "Pickaxe and Pencil: References for the Study of the WPA," 1982 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Book Ben Shahn, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Book A Partridge in a Pear Tree, illustrated by Ben Shahn, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Book Covers, 1976, undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 13) (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Reproductions of Art Work, undated, (5 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 13) (Box 11, Folder 18-22)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1948-1972, undated, (Oversized Material Housed in Box 13 and OV 15) (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Oversized Cover for Book A Vision Shared, 1976, (from Box 11, Folder 17) (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Reproduction of Art Work, undated, (from Box 11, Folder 22) (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Poster of Franklin Delano Roosevelt, undated, (from Box 11, Folder 23) (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Exhibition Announcement for Bernarda Bryson Shahn, 1993, (from Box 10, Folder 59) (Box OV 14)
  - Two Oversized Blue Prints for a Chapel, 1966, (from Box 11, Folder 23) (Box OV 15)
- Scrapbooks, 1945-1978, Series 8:; (Box 11, 13, OV 15; 30 folders)
  Scrapbooks 1-4 contain letters including one from Dag Hammaarskjold, notes, printed material, and photographs documenting the creation of the Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial for which Jonathan Shahn created the large portrait bust. Scrapbooks 5-7 contain notes, reproductions of art work, and photographs of images of the devil for a book by Bernarda Bryson Shahn. Scrapbook 8 contains obituaries for Ben Shahn, assembled by Zackary Gitlin.
  - Scrapbook 1 for the Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial, 1945-1961, undated, (3 folders) (Box 11, Folder 24-26)
  - Scrapbook 2 for the Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial, 1961, (5 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 13) (Box 11, Folder 27-31)
  - Scrapbook 3 for the Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial, 1961, (3 folders) (Box 11, Folder 32-34)
  - Scrapbook 4 for the Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial, 1961-1962, (6 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 13 and OV 15) (Box 11, Folder 35-40)
  - Scrapbook 5: "Images of the Devil," undated, (3 folders) (Box 11, Folder 41-43)
  - Scrapbook 6: "Images of the Devil," 1978, undated, (4 folders) (Box 11, Folder 44-47)
  - Scrapbook 7: "Images of the Devil," 1978, undated, (5 folders) (Box 11, Folder 48-52)
  - Two Oversized Drawings and a Blue Print of the Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial from Scrapbook 2, 1961, (from Box 11, Folder 28) (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Accountant's Report for the Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial from Scrapbook 4, 1962, (from Box 11, Folder 37) (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Blue Print of the Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial from Scrapbook 4, 1962, (from Box 11, Folder 38) (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Scrapbook 8: Ben Shahn Obituaries Assembled by Zackary Gitlin, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Four Oversized Blue Prints of the Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial from Scrapbook 4, 1961, (from Box 11, Folder 38) (Box OV 15)
- Art Work, 1970-2002, Series 9:; (Box 11-13, OV 14; 70 folders)
  Art work includes a sketchbook with annotations, drawings, a portfolio of drawings, lettering designs, watercolor sketches, and layouts for miscellaneous books, booklets, and an exhibition catalog.
  - Sketchbook with Annotations, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - Drawings, undated, (3 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 13) (Box 11, Folder 54-56)
  - Portfolio of Drawings for the Thanks Poster, Bronx Mural, Jamaica, N.Y. Mural, and the Wisconsin (or Missouri) Mural, undated, (6 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 13 and OV 14) (Box 11, Folder 57-62)
  - Lettering Designs, 1982, undated (Box 11, Folder 63)
  - Watercolor Sketches, undated (Box 11, Folder 64)
  - Layout for Book of Poetry with Illustrations by Bernarda Bryson Shahn, undated (Box 11, Folder 65)
  - Layout for Book Which is What, undated (Box 11, Folder 66)
  - Layout for Unidentified Booklet, undated (Box 11, Folder 67)
  - Layout for Exhibition Catalog, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Drawing by JoAnn Jones, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Drawing, undated, (from Box 11, Folder 55) (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Layout Design for Cover of Book The Grindstone of God, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Portfolio Cover, undated, (from Box 11, Folder 57) (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Ten Oversized Portfolio Drawings, undated, (from Box 11, Folder 57) (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Oversized Layout for a Book by Ben Shahn, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Oversized Drawing from the Portfolio, undated, (from Box 11, Folder 57) (Box OV 14)
- Photographs, 1872-1985, Series 10:; (Box 12; 34 folders)
  Photographs are of unidentified ancestors, Ben Shahn, Shahn family members, Ben Shahn with friends and colleagues including Alexander Calder, Helen Hayes, Senator Jacob Javitz, and Nelson Rockefeller, Ben Shahn's studio, exhibition installations, and art work by Bernarda Bryson Shahn, Ben Shahn, and others. There are also press photographs of Franklin Delano Roosevelt and President Bill Clinton and travel photographs of Malta.
  - Photographs of Ancestors, 1872, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of Ben Shahn, Bernarda Bryson Shahn, and Family, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of Ben Shahn and Colleagues, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Press Photographs of Franklin Delano Roosevelt and of President Clinton, 1942, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Miscellaneous Friends, 1944-1967, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Artists' Union Demonstrations, 1934-1935, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 8-10)
  - Photograph of Ben Shahn's Studio, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Exhibition Installations, 1977, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Photographs of Art Work by Bernarda Bryson Shahn, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Photographs of Art Work by Ben Shahn, 1961-1978, undated, (12 folders) (Box 12, Folder 14-25)
  - Photographs of Art Work by Ben Shahn in Bernarda Bryson Shahn 's Collection, undated (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Photographs of Miscellaneous Book Layouts, undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Photographs of Drawings by James Kearns, undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Photographs of Sculpture by James Kearns, undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Photographs of Sculpture by Charles Wells, 1985, undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Photographs of Art Work by Others, undated (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Travel Photographs of Malta, 1980, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 32-34)
  - Miscellaneous Travel Photographs, undated (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, undated (Box 12, Folder 36)